# Gobinath Jegannathan Curriculum Vitae

## Belgiu

117 Avenue de la Couronne, Brussels 1050, Belgium.

+32-465225087

gobinathmj@gmail.com https://gobinathj.github.io/

#### DOCTORAL RESEARCH

### "CMOS based current-assisted detectors with avalanche gain: APDs, SPADs and SiPMs"

For the PhD research, I initially started with research focus on CMOS drivers that can drive a laser to emit very sharp (<1 ns) and high power (>10 W) pulses, which can be used in direct time-of-flight (dTOF) applications. A few months later, due to new ideas and opportunities, I shifted the primary research focus towards a novel single-photon avalanche diode (SPAD) receiver for (dTOF). We came up with the concept of a "current-assisted" SPAD which promises enhanced near infrared sensitivity combined with high speed. Since then, I have been simulating, making variants and characterizing them. A few successful candidate structures for CA-SPADs have be already identified and have been published in peer-reviewed publications and presented at Single photon workshop 2019. My secondary research focus is on realizing high-performance CMOS avalanche photodiodes (APDs) and Silicon photomultipliers (SiPMs) using "current-assistance" technique.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2016 – PRESENT (FT)

Vrije Universiteit Brussel **PhD researcher** 

Expected graduation: August 2021

JULY 2013 - AUGUST 2014 (I YEAR PROJECT)

## Tata institute of fundamental research, Mumbai *Junior research fellow*

This position involved graphene and TMDC nanodevice fabrication and charcterization. During this time, I found a way to use monolayer /bilayer graphene as electrode contacts for WS2 nanotubes and the implementation involved complex trail and error fabrication attempts to realize the device. The end study resulted in a publication in Applied physics letters. (see publication section).

#### **EDUCATION**

2016 - PRESENT Doctor of Philosophy

EXPECTED GRADUATION: AUGUST 2021

Electronics engineering Vrije Universiteit Brussel

2014-2016 Master of Science

Photonics Engineering

Ghent University and Vrije Universiteit Brussel

2009-2013 Bachelor of Technology

Nanotechnology SRM University

#### **SKILLSET**

**Full CMOS process pipeline**: Device physics simulations for sensor pixel, SPICE simulations for readout circuitry, Layout, Test PCB design, Wirebonding, Design of experiments, Experiment automation using python, Device characterization, data analysis and reporting.

**Programming**: Python for data analysis and measurement automation, MATLAB, C#, Basic working knowledge of VHDL.

In addition, I have hands-on experience in working with nanodevice fabrication in a class-roo cleanroom during my time at TIFR. Some selected skills include e-beam lithography, electrode formation using physical vapor deposition, sputtering and atomic layer deposition.

#### **PATENTS**

2016 CMOS VCSEL driver

US10250011B2

2018 Current-assisted SPAD

US20200144436A1

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

**Jegannathan, G.** et al (2019). Current assisted avalanche photo diodes (CAAPDs) with separate absorption and multiplication region in conventional CMOS. *Applied physics letters*, doi.org/10.1063/1.5116102

**Jegannathan, G.** et al (2020). Current-Assisted Single Photon Avalanche Diode (CASPAD) Fabricated in 350 nm Conventional CMOS. *Applied sciences*, doi.org/10.3390/app10062155

**Jegannathan, G\*.** et al (2014). Light matter interaction in

WS2 nanotube-graphene hybrid devices. Applied physics letters, doi.org/10.1063/1.4902983

\*Two equal-contributing first authors

#### CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

**Jegannathan, G.** et al (2019). Current-assisted single photon avalanche diode (CASPAD) in 350 nm CMOS *Single Photon Workshop 2019, Milan.* 

#### REFERENCES

References available on request